seterus.com 2014-06-25

# Seterus, Inc. Privacy Policy

What does Seterus, Inc. do with your personal information? 

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do. 

The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product or service you have with us. This information can include: 

  * Social Security number and income
  * Account balances and payment history
  * Credit history and credit scores

When you are _no longer_ our customer, we continue to share your information as described in this notice. 

All financial companies need to share customers’ personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customers’ personal information; the reasons Seterus, Inc. chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing. 

Reasons we can share your personal information  |  Does Seterus share?  |  Can you limit this sharing?   
---|---|---  
**For our everyday business purposes such as with vendors and affiliates –**   
to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus  |  Yes  |  No   
**For our marketing purposes –**   
to offer our products and services to you  |  No  |  We don't share   
**For joint marketing with other financial companies** |  Yes  |  No   
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes –**   
information about your transactions and experiences  |  No  |  We don't share   
**For our affiliates’ everyday business purposes –**   
information about your credit worthiness  |  No  |  We don't share   
**For our affiliates to market to you** |  No  |  We don't share   
**For nonaffiliates to market to you** |  No  |  We don't share   
  
Questions? 

Call toll-free 866.570.5277 

What we do 

**How does Seterus, Inc. protect my personal information?**

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings. 

  * We educate our employees to treat personal information with care and work to limit access to this information to individuals who need it for the purposes stated in this notice. 

**How does Seterus, Inc. collect my personal information?**

We collect your personal information, for example, when you: 

  * Pay your bills or give us your contact information
  * Make a wire transfer or provide account information
  * Provide your mortgage information

We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies. 

**Why can’t I limit all sharing?**

Federal law gives you the right to limit only: 

  * Sharing for affiliates’ everyday business purposes – information about your creditworthiness
  * Affiliates from using your information to market to you
  * Sharing for nonaffiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing. 

Definitions 

**Affiliates**

Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * _Our parent company is IBM Corporation, which may assist us in our everyday business processes._

**Nonaffiliates**

Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies. 

  * _Nonaffiliates we share with can include credit reporting agencies, insurance companies, investors, loan servicers, direct marketing companies, entities in response to a subpoena or other court order, and professional service organizations or other service providers used to perform services on our behalf._

**Joint marketing**

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

  * _Our joint marketing partners include mortgage companies._

Other important information 

SPECIAL NOTICE FOR CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS: 

Joint Marketing: Unless prohibited by applicable law, we may disclose your personal information to financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements for possible refinancing of your mortgage loan, **unless you opt out** – that is, tell us not to make those disclosures. If you want us not to disclose your personal information for joint marketing or possible refinancing opportunities, please complete the California Opt Out Form and return it to the address indicated. Once we receive this form, we will stop sharing your information with these lenders within a reasonable period of time. 

Online: Personal information collected through this website can include address, email, social security number, and information related to the servicing of your account, such as billing amount and payment history. Seterus may share this personal information with vendors, affiliates, and nonaffiliates as defined in this privacy policy. You can make changes to your personal information under the My Profile tab. If we change our privacy policy, we’ll let you know via this website. Other than the entities specified above, other parties may not collect personally identifiable information about your online activities on this website over time. 

SPECIAL NOTICE FOR VERMONT RESIDENTS: We will not disclose your personal information to financial institutions with which we have joint marketing agreements. 

To view Seterus’s hours of operation, please visit our [Contact Us](http://www.seterus.com/Home/ContactUs) page.

Seterus NMLS ID Number: 787641   

THIS COMMUNICATION IS FROM A DEBT COLLECTOR AS WE SOMETIMES ACT AS A DEBT COLLECTOR. WE ARE ATTEMPTING TO COLLECT A DEBT AND ANY INFORMATION OBTAINED WILL BE USED FOR THAT PURPOSE. HOWEVER, IF YOU ARE IN BANKRUPTCY OR RECEIVED A BANKRUPTCY DISCHARGE OF THIS DEBT, THIS LETTER IS NOT AN ATTEMPT TO COLLECT THE DEBT, BUT NOTICE OF POSSIBLE ENFORCEMENT OF OUR LIEN AGAINST THE COLLATERAL OR FOR INFORMATIONAL PURPOSES ONLY. IF YOU RECEIVE OR HAVE RECEIVED A DISCHARGE OF THIS DEBT THAT IS NOT REAFFIRMED IN A BANKRUPTCY PROCEEDING, YOU WILL NOT BE PERSONALLY RESPONSIBLE FOR THE DEBT. HOWEVER, THE LIEN AGAINST THE PROPERTY SECURING THIS DEBT MAY REMAIN ON THE PROPERTY UNTIL THE AMOUNT OWING ON THE LOAN IS PAID. COLORADO: SEE [WWW.COLORADOATTORNEYGENERAL.GOV/CA](http://www.coloradoattorneygeneral.gov/CA) FOR INFORMATION ABOUT THE COLORADO FAIR DEBT COLLECTION PRACTICES ACT. Seterus, Inc. maintains a local office at 355 Union Boulevard, Suite 250, Lakewood, CO 80228. The office’s phone number is 888.738.5576. NEW YORK CITY: 1411669, 1411665, 1411662. TENNESSEE: This collection agency is licensed by the Collection Service Board of the Department of Commerce and Insurance. Seterus, Inc. is licensed to do business at 14523 SW Millikan Way, Beaverton, OR.

Special Notice Regarding Information Subject to the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act 

This notice is in accordance with federal privacy law. If your account is subject to the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act (FDCPA) or other applicable laws regarding information sharing or communicating with others, Seterus, Inc. will only communicate with others in accordance with the FDCPA and the other applicable laws. 

Requires Adobe Acrobat. Get it [here](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep2.html).

Effective: December 2013
